Mattia Righetti

☑ mattiarighetti@outlook.com 🌐 mattrighetti.com 🦃 mattrighetti 🛅 mattia-righetti

What I Do

Software Engineering

- · Develop backend systems that are reliable and perform well and are easy to maintain. I have experience with different languages, lately I have been mostly working with Go and Rust. I have experience in working with microservices.
- · I contribute to open source projects, I am an active maintainer in the Network Health team at the Tor Project where I work on the Network Status APIs
- I develop apps for macOS and iOS, mostly as a hobby.
- I setup CI/CD pipelines on GitHub and GitLab to help testing, benchmarking and deploying services.
- I help with frontend: I have worked with React, TS, JS and HTML/CSS in a lot of personal projects.

Experience

Anthropos

Backend Engineer | May 2023 - now | Lugano, Switzerland

- Implemented REST APIs for different Anthropos services, later migrated most of the user-facing APIs to GraphQL and internal microservices APIs to RPC
- · Improved and worked on Anthropos microservices that were responsible for job simulations orchestrated with AI, implemented GraphQL servers for each microservice and bridged their features with the pre-existing RPC APIs
- · Integrated Stripe's payment processing capabilities with our backend infrastructure
- Setup Apollo Router using graph federation, established a standardized way to version and deploy supergraph when microservices changed their GraphQL schema
- Lead development of the Anthropos iOS application
- Redesigned and enhanced form data parsing and autofill capabilities of the Anthropos Chrome Extension using React. Improved user experience and made it easier for customers to efficiently manage and automate job applications

Amazon

SDE Intern | June 2022 - Nov 2022 | Luxembourg, Luxembourg

- · Developed and optimized new backend APIs that automated most of the interactions that other teams had with our service, making it faster, more efficient and available 24/7.
- Designed and developed a web application to showcase our team's APIs and services which made the onboarding process for stakeholders smooth and enjoyable.
- Deployed and maintained OSRM service to support team services that needed to scale and had internal API limitations.
- Data pipelines management and data manipulation with Apache Airflow, AWS Glue and AWS ECR. Improved parallelisms of ETL pipelines.
- Setup multiple pipeline to manage CI/CD of team services with the use of AWS CDK and AWS CloudFormation.

Politecnico di Milano

Fullstack Engineer | Jun 2018 - Sep 2021 | Milan, Italy

- Designed and maintained database to support department required features.
- · Developed web application that made interaction with the database more intuitive and quick for all the students of the department.

- Developed backend REST APIs used by the web application to interact with the database.
- VPS administration and maintenance including domain registration and networking setup.

Education

I have a BSc in Computer Science and I am finishing my MSc in Computer Science, graduating from Politecnicno di Milano, IT.

About Me

My interest in software started with Android phones, I was 13 and with my HTC Desire I had a very active presence on XDA forum (my account is still there indeed matt95) trying out custom ROMs and helping others with different guides that I wrote. Not long after that, I built my first computer all by myself. With that, I started programming a couple of months later. Java was my very first language, I remember reading the Java 7 book during biology classes in high school. Curiosity for good software has been driving me from that day forward.